The Tragedy of M
もう もう二度とこの手を放しません
I will never let go of this hand again.
Let this night of love last forever, with the galaxy as our pillow.
銀河を巻くように
いつまでも変わらぬ愛の夜を
We are two as one.
私達は二人で一人
Oh, let our love soar past the twinkling stars.
空の果て 輝く星の向こうへ
With as many kisses as there are stars.
瞬く星の数だけ キスを
もうー 離れない
Together, forever.
行こう 天かける白鳥の翼で
Fly, with wings that transcend the heavens.
Let us go, to the land of our eternal night.
行きましょう 二人だけの夜の国へ
くるくる回る
<< kurukuru mawaru kimi no hitomi >>
<< Round and round, your eyes wander around >>
君の瞳探して回る
<< sagashite mawaru eki no home >>
<< Searching around the station's platforms >>
駅のホーム
<< hibiku fanfare >>
<< The sound of fanfare from afar >>
響くファンファーレ
ガラガラ音を立てる街
<< garagara oto wo tateru machi >>
<< The clamorous city making noise >>
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
<< toriaezu mimi wo kashite ita no >>
<< I tried to keep an ear out for all this >>
<< mousugu kieru hazu no sekai ni >>
<< In a world that's about to end >>
もうすぐ消えるはずの世界に
御免ね
<< gomen ne >>
<< I'm sorry >>
もう二度と会えないようなそんな気がして
<< mou nido to aenai youna sonna ki ga shite >>
<< I just had a feeling I would never see you again >>
運命が笑う
<< unmei ga warau >>
<< Fate is laughing at us >>
臨界点突破してんだ
<< rinkaiten toppa shiten da >>
<< I'm already past the point of no return >>
限界なら既に去って
<< genkai nara sude ni satte >>
<< Far over my limit >>
絶対的支配だって
<< zettaiteki shihai datte >>
<< Even your absolute control has >>
崩壊
<< houkai >>
<< Crumbled >>
終末理論は机上の空論でしかないって
<< shuumatsu riron wa kijou no kuuron shika naitte >>
<< "The end of the world is nothing but a hypothesis" >>
ゼロとイチの世界線の果てから
<< 0 to 1 no sekaisen no hate kara sakebu yo >>
<< Is what I'm crying out from other side of the binary world line >>
叫ぶよ
もうすぐ君が会いにくるような気がして
<< mou sugu kimi ga ai ni kuru you na ki ga shite >>
<< I have a feeling you'll come see me soon >>
僕は目を閉じるよ
<< boku wa me wo tojiru yo >>
<< So I will be waiting with my eyes closed >>
本字幕由诸神字幕组(www.kamigami.org)制作,仅供学习交流之用
若您喜欢本作品,请支持正版影像制品
---诸神字幕组---
时间轴：wcaster  压制：wcaster
日听 xHunter 翻译：小音 校对：要命的小宇、木落
飛んでイスタンブール
We "Flew to Istanbul."
君の旦那様は本当に御気の毒
I feel sorry for your husband.
こんな気持ち 女同士でだけ分かち合えない
You can only share this feeling with another woman.
うんざりだわ
I've grown tired of you.
前から思ってたけど
I've suspected it for a while, but you really are a boring one-trick pony.
貴方ってワンパターンでつまらない
そんなテクで女が満足するとでも思ってるの
Do you really think you can satisfy a woman with those moves?
ま…待ってくれ
W-Wait!
僕達は永遠のパートナーじゃなかったの
I thought we were eternal partners!
舞台の上もベッドの上も二人で一人
On stage and in bed!
Two as one!
何勘違いしてるの
You're sadly mistaken.
私は飽きた男役は二度と抱かないの
I never sleep with actors I've grown tired of again.
そんなのは嘘だ
That can't be true!
Yuri, say it ain't so!
ね 嘘って言ってよ
本当にいいんですか
Are you sure about this?
If you break up with me...
僕と別れちゃって
貴方の体の秘密 何処かで誰かが噂するかもしれませんよ
Someone, somewhere might spread a rumor about your body's secret.
最後まで残念な男役ね
You really are pathetic to the core.
ノー 待ってくれ
No! Wait!
愛してるんだ モナムール
I love you, mon amour!
この世界は残酷なルールに支配されている
This world is governed by cruel rules.
求められる物と求められない物
The needed and the unneeded.
その二つを分けるラインが私には見える
I can see the line that divides them.
だからこそ私はファビュラスに成功した
That's why I've succeeded fabulously.
いまや私が特別な存在
I have become a special presence.
もう誰も容易には私に近づく事など出来ない
No one will be allowed to touch me as they please again.
私の心には決して誰にも触れさせない
No one will be allowed to reach my heart.
私は過去を捨てた
I've abandoned my past!
嘘よ
It's a lie...
この世界は皆嘘で出来てる
This world is made of lies.
未来永劫誰も私のことを本当に求めたりなんかしない
No one will ever need me, not for all eternity.
貴方だけだった
You were the only one...
貴方だけが私を美しいと言ってくれた
The only one who told me I was beautiful.
会いたい 今すぐ貴方に
I want to see you.
Right now.
きっと会えるわよね
We will meet again, right?
だって 約束したじゃない
I mean, we promised...
私達の繋がりは永遠だって
That our bond would be eternal.
晶馬君
Shoma!
もうー すごい待ったんだぞ
Sheesh! You kept me waiting for so long!
Did Himari get discharged yet?
ひまりちゃん もう退院した
何度かメールしたんだけど 全然返ってく
I emailed her few times, but she's not respon-
Sorry.
御免
I'm in a hurry.
ちょっと急いでるから
ちょ…ちょっと待って
W-Wait!
Why...
どうして どうしてあたしを避けるの
Why are you avoiding me?
You're not answering your phone or returning my emails.
電話しても出ないし メールも返してくれないし
しょうがないだろう
What did you expect?
だって 僕は君に償うことなんか出来ないんだから
I mean, I can never make it up to you.
償う 何よ それ
Make up? For what?
That's not funny.
やめてよ そんな冗談
じゃ 僕にどうしろっていうんだよ
What do you want from me then?
百回 千回 土下座しろっていうのか
Should I get on my knees and apologize a hundred, no, a thousand times?
それで気が済むなら遣ってもいいさ
でもそうじゃないんだろう
I'd do it, if that's what it took.
その程度のことで 君は僕達を許したり出来ないだろう
But that's not what you want, right?
That's not nearly enough to earn your forgiveness, right?
許す
Forgiveness?
あたし そんなこと考えたこともないわ
The thought never even crossed my mind.
いや 君は絶対に僕達を許さない
No, you will never be able to forgive us.
僕達家族が徹底的に不幸になって 駄目になるのを見届けるまで
You will continue to monitor our family's misfortunes
監視を続けるんだろう
until we've met complete and utter ruin.
皆そうだった
Everyone did.
皆僕達から離れていって
Everyone abandoned us.
僕達は兄弟だけで生きるしかなくて
The three of us were forced to live on our own.
あたし
I'm... not like them.
そんなじゃないよ
I wouldn't abandon you over that.
あたし そんなことで晶馬君達から離れたりしないよ
ひまりちゃんのことだって　大好きだし
I love Himari too.
やめてくれよ
Enough already!
そういうのもう嫌なんだ
I've had enough of this.
これ以上表面的な言葉で傷つけ合うことになんの意味があるんだよ
Why do we continue to hurt each other with superficial words?
もう 僕達は会わない方がいいんだ
We shouldn't see each other anymore.
傷つく
Hurt?
そっか あたし自分のことばかり考えちゃってた
You're right. I've only been thinking about myself.
晶馬君 あたしと話をすると 傷つくんだ
It hurts you… to talk to me...
御免ね あたし 鈍かったね
I'm sorry.
I was being… dense.
We're done here.
もういいだろう
To'oh General Hospital
出来た
Done!
ジャン
Tada!
暖かマフラー 完成
Warm scarf, complete!
余は満足でおじゃる
'tis satisfactory.
これは雲雀ちゃん こっちは光莉ちゃんに
This one is for Hibari.
This for Hikari.
喜んでくれるかな
I hope they'll like them.
約束の金だ
Here's the money we agreed on.
痺れるね
How electrifying.
よくこの短期間でこれだけの金を
I'm impressed you managed to come up with so much money in such a short time.
じゃ これを妹さんに
Then, I'll give this to your sister.
Is what I'd like to say, but...
と思ったけど
これじゃ少し足りないな
This isn't quite enough.
Last time, you said...
この間はこれで
いいえ
Market price fluctuates.
相場は生き物だからね
毎日 世界中の子供達の命が相場によって仕分けられてゆく
Every day, the market sorts the lives of children around the world into
助かる子供 助からない子供
the salvageable and the unsalvageable.
分かった
All right.
今日中に何とかする
I'll come up with the money by the end of the day.
頼もしい
I'll look forward to it.
それでひまりは何時退院出来るんだ
When can Himari be discharged, then?
世界の秘密が明かされた時
When the secrets of the world are revealed.
そうだね
Well, after a few more ampules, she'll be well enough to go home at least.
マア 後数回このアンプルを使えば
家に戻るくらいは出来るかな
さて 御姫様 御機嫌はいかが
How are you this fine morning, princess?
麗しい とは言えないか
Not so fine, I guess.
My, my.
あれれ
どうしたの これ
What happened here?
捨てたの
I threw them away.
But you worked so hard on them.
一生懸命編んでたのに
They're well-made.
よく出来てるじゃないか
もったいない
What a waste!
There will be divine retribution!
お化けが出ます
誰か大切な人へのプレゼントかと思ってた
I thought they were presents for people you cared about?
もういいの
It doesn't matter anymore.
どうして
How come?
私の編んだマフラーなんて誰も喜ばないし
No one would like getting my hand-made scarves.
じゃ 僕がもらおうかな
Then I'll take them.
What?
痺れるね
How electrifying.
なかなかいい
Quite comfortable.
You're so awesome, Dr. Sanetoshi!
さすがです　眞悧先生
You're, like, totally wrapped up!
物凄く巻き熟しています
だよね
I know, right?
だって 捨てちゃうんだろう だったら
You're throwing them away, aren't you?
So...
Whatever.
い…いいよ 別に
How to Throw Things
Away Properly
嫌だわ はやくすり潰さないと
Gosh, I must crush it soon.
The sooner, the better.
なるべく早い方がいいね
日記の半分 その女が持ってるって情報は確かでしょうね
Are you certain that woman has the other half of the diary?
マア 痺れるだろう
Yes.
Isn't it electrifying?
ええ ぞくぞくするわ
Yes. It sends a shiver down my spine.
エスメラルド 女狐狩りの時間よ
Esmeralda, it's time to hunt the fox.
でもその前に
But first...
"You kept me waiting" Get his attention by acting cute!
馬鹿 私の馬鹿 馬鹿 馬鹿
Idiot.
I'm such a stupid, stupid idiot!
何がぶりっ子だ 何が待ったんだそうだ
Trying to act cute!
"You kept me waiting?"
Yuri Tokikago uses a spinning
drum washing machine.
Yuri Tokikago
uses a spinning
drum
washing machine.
Yuri Tokikag
ses a spinning
drum
washi
machine.
ああああ 言うちゃった
I can't believe I said it!
乗りなさい
Hop in.
Shoma says it hurts him to see or hear me.
あたしを見ると あたしと話すと
晶馬君傷つくって
あたし 晶馬君のあんな顔見たくないから
I don't want to see his sad face.
I don't want to be the cause of it.
させたくないから
だから もう二度と会えないんだって
So...
I realized we should never meet again.
それがあたし達の運命なのかなって
Maybe that's our fate.
You're in love.
恋をしてるのね 可哀そうに
You poor girl.
But first loves rarely work out.
でも初恋って 大抵実らないものよ
I had someone like that too.
私にもかつてそういう人がいたわ
百合さんに
You did?
Just so you know, it wasn't Tabuki.
言っとくけど 多蕗のことじゃないわよ
What happened?
その人は
Disappeared...
消えてしまったわ ある日突然私の前から
One day, without telling me.
So I know exactly how you feel.
だからリンゴちゃんの辛い気持ちとってもよく分かるの
But did you know?
だけどね 知ってる
そんな時は女同士パーッとファビュラスマックスするのが一番なのよ
A Fabulous Max girls' night out is the best solution!
Today's
Slogan
Going in may be fine, fine, but returning would be scary
確かに
It's all there.
Now I can get a hold of Himari's medicine.
これでひまりの薬は手に入る
よし 次の仕事の件だわ
About the next job...
Gosh, I must crush them soon!
嫌だわ はやくすり潰さなくちゃ
自分のしていることが分かっているの
Do you have any idea what you're getting yourself into?
You're standing on the edge of an iceberg right now.
貴方は今氷山の端っこに立たされているよ
これ以上踏み込んだら
One more step and you'll fall into the sea.
海に落ちるだけよ
お前には関係ない
It's none of your business.
I'll pay for it, if you need money.
お金が必要なら 私が払う
Okay?
それでいいでしょう
As if I'm going to use the Natsume clan's money.
夏芽家の金なんか使えるか
I see.
そう
Very well.
いいよ じゃ
Then I'll crush you
貴方が海に落ちてシャチの餌になる前に
before you fall and become seal food.
この私がすり潰してあげる
It only takes one word to nip misconduct in the bud. We're all in this together
What's so good about her?
あんな小娘の何処がいいの
What are you talking about?
何のことだ
Don't play dumb.
おとぼけは止して
私は貴方だけを見つめてきた
I've had my eyes trained on you my whole life.
I know everything about you.
私は貴方の全てを知っている
言ってあげましょうか
Do I have to spell it out for you?
You love her!
貴方はあの女を愛している
Yes, hopelessly so.
そう どうしようもなくね
一体誰の話だ
Who are you talking about?
I just want to save my precious family.
俺はただ大切な自分の家族を救いたいだけだ
So, it just can't be me?
どうしても私じゃだめってことね
Stop this nonsense.
いい加減にしろよ
Fine.
よろしくてよ
I'll seize happiness in my own way.
私は私の遣り方で幸せを掴むから
I'll save Mario for sure.
マリオさんは必ず私が救ってみせる
ようこそ 時籠様
Welcome, Ms. Tokikago.
いつもごひいきに ありがとうございます
Thank you for your continued patronage.
Tokikago
Yuri
Ringo
Are you on a trip with your sister?
まあ ご姉妹でご旅行ですか
Yes.
ええ
今日一日私が貴方のお姉さん
I'll be your older sister for the day.
Or would you rather not?
そういうの 嫌
あっ いいえ ちょっと嬉しいです
No, that sounds like fun.
I think so too.
私も可愛い妹が出来て 嬉しいわ
I like having a cute little sister.
じゃ まずは一休みして
Let's take a break and then go to the hot spring.
それから  温泉ね
あっ その前にリンゴちゃんのお母様にご連絡しないと
We have to call your mother first.
さあ バリバリ骨休みするわよ
Let's refresh body and soul.
This feels great!
気持ちいいですね
そっ よかった
Oh? That's good.
Washing away sadness and pain is the best solution.
悲しい事 辛い事はこうしてお湯で流してしまうのが一番よね
あの
Um, can I ask you one thing?
一つ聞いてもいいですか
Go ahead.
どうぞ
多蕗さんとは何処で知り合ったんですか
Where did you meet Tabuki?
I mean, you're a star. You two are worlds apart.
なんていうか
百合さん スターだし
住んでる世界が違うから
あら いうわね
You can be pretty blunt, huh?
彼とはね 幼馴染なの
He's a childhood friend of mine.
We were classmates in elementary school.
小学校の同級生
Huh?
えっ
Then, you knew my sister, Momoka?
じ…じゃ
姉の事 桃果の事も
Yes, I did.
ええ 知ってるわ
Very well.
とてもよくね
姉は どんな子でしたか
What was she like?
A vast field of flowers peaking out
from beyond a dry, desolate desert.
渇き切った砂漠の向こうに見えた一面の花畑
A single light shining in the cold, dark night.
凍える暗い夜に見つけた蝋燭の火
桃果は私の世界を変えてくれた
Momoka changed my world.
彼女といれば
When I was with her, everything seemed brighter.
どんなものもキラキラ光って見えた
世界は愛すべきものに満ちている
The world is filled with things to be loved.
そう この私も含めて
Including myself.
多蕗さんもそんなこと言ってました
Tabuki said something like that too.
やっぱり姉は凄い子だったんですね
She really was an amazing person.
私とは全然違う
Unlike me.
ちょっと落ち込んじゃうな
That's kind of depressing.
Oh? That's not true at all.
あら そんなことないわよ
ええ
姉妹って 不思議ね
Sisters sure are mysterious.
リンゴちゃん 貴方は桃果と同じ香がする
Ringo, you have the same scent as Momoka.
Same... scent?
同じ香
I wanted to become Momoka.
あたし 桃果に成りたかったんです
Why?
どうして
多蕗さんは桃果が好きだから
Because Tabuki loves Momoka.
マア 妻の私にそれを言う
Geez, I'm his wife, you know.
Oh, I'm sorry.
あ　御免なさい
Don't worry, I'll make an exception and forgive you.
いいわ 特別に許してあげる
あの
Um...
What is it?
何
どうして多蕗さんと結婚したんですか
Why did you marry Tabuki?
Because I love him.
愛しているから
Of course.
ですよね
The Tragedy of M
Takes Flight
I'll take off
Seeking true love
That was a lie.
嘘
本当は私達 仮面夫婦なの
The truth is, our marriage is just for show.
Huh?
えっ
Kidding.
なんてね
But the truth is...
でも本当は
Huh?
はい
We're actually bound by the wheel of fate.
私達 運命の輪で繋がれているの
What?
えっ
Is there––
他には 他には何かありますか
Is there anything else?
貴方が桃果に似ているところ
About you that's similar to Momoka?
一杯あるわよ
All sorts of things.
Really?
本当ですか
ほら そうやって興味がある時絶対に視線をそらさない癖
You see, the way you never look away when you're truly interested.
It's just like her!
そっくりよ
R-Really?
そ…そうですか
That too!
ほら それも
The habit of playing with your bangs when you blush.
照れたりすると前髪を弄る癖
That kind of makes me happy.
なんか ちょっと嬉しいです
My mommy and daddy never told me much about Momoka.
パパもママも桃果のことあんまり教えてくれなかったから
そう
I see.
Hey, do you still want to become Momoka?
ねえ まだ桃果に成りたい
What?
え
Uh... huh?
あ-れ-
嫌だ こんなところまで瓜二つ
Oh, my!
Even your hand is almost a carbon copy!
The shape of your fingers, even the curve of your nails!
指の形 爪の白い半月まで
Ringo... How fabulous you are!
リンゴちゃん なんてファビュラスなの
百合 さん
Yuri?
Nobody knows the real me and still thinks I'm beautiful.
本当の私を知ってそれでも私を美しいなんて言う人はいない
Lies, lies, lies.
嘘 嘘 嘘
This world is made of lies.
この世界は皆嘘
Beauty alone is truth.
美しい物だけが本当
So, no one loves me.
だから誰も私の事なんて愛していないの
But... But...
だけど だけど
Momoka was the only person who knew all about me,
桃果はこの世界でたった一人私の全てを知っていて
and still said I was beautiful.
それでも 私の事を美しいと言ってくれた
She alone accepted the true me.
彼女だけが本当の私を認めてくれたの
Momoka was my soul mate.
桃果は私の運命の人だった
I want to see her.
会いたい
Whatever it takes, I want to see Momoka one more time.
どうしても桃果にもう一度会いたい
そうよ 私は信じない
That's right.
I won't believe it.
Momoka is not dead.
桃果は死んでなんかいない
The time has finally come.
ようやくこの時が来たわ
Everything is as written on Momoka's diary.
全ては桃果の日記に記されていた通り
Yuri - In front of my condo - The night of the storm - In the pouring rain, the true identity of the  female rider who stole half of Ringo's diary is–
Ringo.
リンゴちゃん
I want you to become Momoka.
貴方には桃果に成って欲しいの
But, I'm sure you'll hate me when you see my true self.
でも貴方は本当の私を見たら
きっと私を嫌いになるわ
So I want to mess you up...
だから 貴方をめちゃくちゃにして
I'll give you a body that can't survive without me.
私から離れられない体にしてあげる
The Princess of Lies
黒い予感が 近づいてくる
kuroi yokan ga  chikazuitekuru
Bad news is drawing near
kutsu wo hibikase  sunatate
Footsteps echo and kick up clouds of dust
靴を響かせ 砂煙立て
warui yume ga  tsuzuku to omotta
I thought I was still having a bad dream
悪い夢が 続くと思ってた
やけに激しく風が吹き荒れた
yakeni hageshiku  kaze ga fukiareta
An awfully violent wind blew in
陽が上り　陽が沈む
hi ga nobori  hi ga shizumu
The sun rises and the sun sinks
静かだった 日々が消える
shizukadatta hibi ga kieru
The quiet days have vanished
omae omou  yoru ga aru kedo
You might think night exists, but
お前思う 夜があるけど
サーチライトがつけ狙う
saachiraito ga  tsukenerau
The searchlight is still on the prowl
achikochi de kuudetaa ga okoridasu
Coup d'étas are springing up every which where
あちこちで  クーデターが起り出す
achikochi de kuudetaa ga okoridasu
Coup d'étas are springing up every which where
あちこちで  クーデターが起り出す
darou
Right...
だろう
darou
Right...
だろう
darou
Right...
だろう
darou
Right...
だろう
Are you really gone?
君は本当に行ってしまったのか
That's a world unknown to me.
そこは僕の知らない世界だよ
What can caterpillars see when they turn into butterflies?
蛹が蝶になったら 何が見えるんだい
生存戦略 凄い待ったんだぞ
Lily Hoshino
Survival Strategy. You kept me waiting for sooo long!